Our Monte Carlo control algorithm will draw
蒙特卡洛控制算法
inspiration from generalized policy iteration.
收到广义策略迭代的启发
We'll begin with the policy evaluation step.
我们从策略评估步骤开始
We've already somewhat addressed how to accomplish this
我们已经知道如何实现这一步
and you implemented it in part two of the mini project.
并且你已经在迷你项目的第二部分实现这一步
In your implementation, the agent needs to play blackjack about
在你的实现中 智能体需要猜测大概 5000 次
5,000 times to get a good estimate of the value function.
以便很好地估算值函数
In the context of policy iteration,
对于策略迭代
this seems like way too long to spend evaluating a policy before trying to improve it.
这样的话 在完善策略之前 似乎花费了太长的时间来评估策略
Maybe it would make more sense to improve
或许在每次猜测之后
the policy after every individual game of blackjack.
都完善策略更合理
In that case, we could initialize the value of
在这种情况下 我们可以将每个状态动作对的
each state action pair to zero and have some starting policy.
值初始猜测设为 0 并获得起始策略
Then, we could use that policy to generate an episode.
然后使用该策略生成一个阶段
When that episode finishes,
当该阶段结束时
we could update the value function.
我们可以更新值函数
Then, the value function could be used to improve the policy.
并使用该值函数完善策略
That new policy could then be used to generate the next episode, and so on.
然后使用该新策略生成下个阶段 等等
To do this well, we'll have to change our algorithm for policy evaluation.
为了有效地完成这一过程 我们需要更改策略评估算法
We'll begin by digging deeper into our current algorithm.
我们将首先深入了解当前算法
Remember that we begin by running many episodes.
我们先执行多个阶段
Then, we look at some state action pair.
然后查看一些状态动作对
We calculate the return that followed in each case and then take the average.
我们计算每种情况之后的回报 然后取平均值
As a more general case,
作为更一般的情况
say we visited the state action pair some number and times.
假设该状态动作对经历了一定的次数
We'll denote the corresponding returns by x1,
将相应的回报表示为 x1 x2
x2 all the way up to xn.
一直到 xn
Then, our value function estimate is calculated as the average of those values.
然后通过对这些值取平均值 计算值函数逼近结果
We'll denote it with a MU n where the n
表示为 μn
just helps us to remember that we visited the pair n times.
n 表示经历该状态动作对 n 次
And so Instead of calculating that average at the end of all the episodes,
我们不再在所有阶段结束之后计算该平均值
maybe what we could do instead is iteratively update the estimate after every visit.
而是在每次经历之后都迭代更新估值
So the first time that we visited,
首次经历时
whatever the return was, that's our estimate.
无论回报是多少 都是我们的估值
Then the second time we visit,
第二次经历时
we can update the estimate to be the average of x1 and x2.
我们将估值更新为 x1 和 x2 的平均值
And for an arbitrary number of visits K,
在经过随机 K 次经历后
we just take the average of all the values x1 through xk.
我们对 x1 到 xk 的所有值取平均值
And our final estimate,
最终的估值
will just be exactly what we'd end up with if we'd waited
将相当于等到所有阶段结束后
to calculate anything until all the episodes finished.
获得的结果
And so let's see if we can figure out how
我们来看看能否以更加高效的计算方式
to accomplish this in a computationally efficient way.
完成这一流程
And towards that goal, we'll have to do a little bit of math.
为此 我们需要进行一些数学变换
We'll begin by remembering how we calculate the estimate for the return.
首先需要回顾如何计算回报的估值
In particular, the Kth estimate is
具体而言 第 K 项估值是
just the average of the returns that followed from the first K visits.
前 K 次经历之后的回报的平均值
Then, we'll notice we can rewrite the sum of the first K returns,
然后 我们可以将前 K 次回报的和
as the sum of the first K minus one returns plus the Kth return.
重写为前 K-1 次回报的和加上第 K 次回报
After that, we can re-express the sum of the first K minus one terms,
接着 我们将前 K-1 的和这一项
as the K minus first mean times K minus one.
重写为 K 减去第一个均值并乘以 K-1
It's just a simple rearrangement of the terms to get the last line.
只需简单变换下就能获得最后一行
Now this equation expresses the Kth mean in
这个等式表示第 K 项均值
terms of the K minus first mean and the Kth return.
对 K 减去第一个均值和第 K 项回报
And we'll use this formula to design
我们将使用该公式设计一个算法
an algorithm that keeps a running mean of the returns.
用于不断求回报的平均值
We begin by initializing the mean to zero.
先将均值初始化为 0
We'll also need to keep track of the number of
还需要记录平均值中已经包含的
returns that we've included in the average already.
回报的数量
So at the beginning,
一开始
we'll initialize that to zero.
我们将该值初始化为 0
Then we enter a while loop at every point we increment K by
然后进入 while 循环
one and then use the most recent return x of K to update the mean.
每次使 K 加一 然后使用最近的回报 xk 更新均值
And that's it. Now while it's not entirely clear yet
就这样 虽然暂时不能完全清楚
exactly how to use this in the context of Monte Carlo control,
如何在蒙特卡洛控制中使用该算法
this algorithm will come in very useful soon.
但是 很快该算法就会变得非常实用